天啊  真不敢相信哈雷已经这么大了
Oh, my God, I can't believe how big Halley's getting.
对啊  霍华德在哪呢
Yeah-- where's Howard?
他在给麦克换尿布
He's changing Michael.
搞定  分享个有趣小知识
A-All done. You know, fun fact,
你们知道男婴儿可以往空中撒尿吗
did you know baby boys can pee straight up?
长大的男孩也可以
Grown-up boys, too.
我们为啥要击掌这事
Why would we high-five that?
你们俩还好吗
So how are you guys?
很好啊
Really good.
除了我们去超市买东西时
Except for when we went grocery shopping,
结账的店员问我预产期是什么时候
and the checkout lady asked when I was due.
但你应对得很好啊
But you handled it well.
如果你们需要人帮忙  我很乐意过去
Well, if you guys need help, I'd be happy to come over.
谢谢了  但我们想尽量在回岗位前
Oh, thanks, but we're really trying to enjoy this family time
多享受这天伦之乐
before we both go back to work.
好吧  我们都很想你们
Okay, well, we all miss you.
-我们也想你们  -再见
- You guys, too. - ?Bye.
要命了  看到他们一家和乐融融
Boy, seeing them all together like that
让人家的生物钟疯狂加速到想要...
has got my biological clock ticking like crazy.
男人好像没有...
Yeah, I don't think men have...
人家有
I do.
-你们好  -来啦
- Hi. - Hello.
你们来啦
Hey, guys.
好消息  我们有邀请函了
Good news, we have save the date cards.
居然没用我的书法  有意思
Huh, didn't go with my calligrapher. Interesting.
这图案是什么
What is this picture?
是把我们俩大脑的核磁共振成像
Oh, it's an MRI of our brains photoshopped
修到看起来像在接吻
to look like they're kissing.
是不是太性感火辣了
Is it too sexy?
太难以形容了
It's too something.
大家  是5月12号  太迫不及待了
Guys, May 12, that's exciting.
-是啊  -你们定好在哪举行了吗
- I know. - Do you guys have a location yet?
你们时间所剩不多啊
'Cause you don't have a lot of time.
我们俩花了9个月才选出个日期
Hey, it took us nine months to pick a date,
又花了一周来决定大脑能不能加上嘴唇
and a week to decide if brains can have lips on them,
少唧唧歪歪  配合就是了
so get in the boat and row.
第十一季  第十七集
麦克睡着了
Michael's out.
哈雷也睡着了
So is Halley.
老天啊  他太可爱了
Oh, my God, he's so cute.
她也是
So is she.
交换吗
Switch?
好
Yeah.
老天啊  他太可爱了
Oh, my God, he's so cute.
她也是
So is she.
我好爱他们
I just love them so much.
我也是
Me, too.
我的心脏感觉都要被萌炸了
My heart feels like it's gonna explode.
当然啦  我吃了那么多牛腩  总有一天会炸
Of course, it's full of brisket, so it probably will.
我本来都不知道我这个人
Oh, I didn't even know I was capable
居然可以这么爱某一个人
of loving someone so much.
多过爱我吗
More than me?
我耍你呢
I'm just messing with you.
我爱他们绝对多过爱你无数倍
I totally love them more than you.
我理解
I get that.
我愿意为他们挡子弹
I would take a bullet for them.
但我也愿意为你严重断手断脚
But I would get seriously mutilated for you.
嘴真甜
That's sweet.
但先说好  如果你哪天真的残了
But you should know, if you got seriously mutilated,
我可能会甩了你
I might dump you.
你不甩才真是疯了
You'd be crazy not to.
我好手好脚时也不是什么人中龙凤
Even unmutilated, I'm no prize.
我对我们选出来的大喜之日十分满意
You know, I'm really happy with our wedding date.
月份的平方等于日期的
The month squared equals the square of the sum of the members
质因子的和的平方
of the set of prime factors of the day.
是不是超浪漫
Isn't that romantic?
对啊  就像莎士比亚那首十四行诗写的
Yes, it's like that Shakespeare sonnet,
出自莎士比亚十四行诗第18 "我怎能将你与夏日媲美"
"我怎能将你与
"Shall I compare thee to a day
大喜之日兼奇怪数学问题媲美"
that's also a really weird math problem."
太遗憾你只是在挖苦了
It's a shame you're joking.
不然本来很适合在我们婚礼朗诵呢
That'd be a lovely reading at our ceremony.
我们只剩两个月时间找场地了
Well, we only have two months to find a venue,
而我有个想法
and I had a thought.
加州理工的雅典娜学术俱乐部怎么样
What about the Athenaeum club at Caltech?
阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦曾是会员
Albert Einstein was a member there.
-环境很美  -是啊
- It's beautiful. ?- Yeah,
而且阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦曾是会员
and Albert Einstein was a member there.
还很近
It's close.
该俱乐部的史上首次正式晚餐  宾客有爱因斯坦与三位诺贝尔奖得主
而且阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦曾是会员
And Albert Einstein was a member there.
现在你听起来像是个想结婚的女人了
Now you sound like a woman who wants to get married.
所以你有兴趣吗
So you're interested?
当然啦
Oh, of course.
可是那个俱乐部十分难进
Yeah, but that club is extremely exclusive.
你知道莱纳德试着帮我们申请好多年了吗
You know, Leonard's been trying to get us in there for years,
但都没成功过
but no luck.
这就奇怪了
Well, that's odd.
我打去询问时  他们表示很乐意带我们看看
When I called, they said they'd be excited to give us a tour.
好吧  去看一下也没损失
Well, I suppose we can give it a look,
如果最后没成功  我听说那附近
and if it doesn't work out, I hear that there is
有一家中餐馆以前爱因斯坦是常客
a nearby Chinese restaurant that Einstein used to frequent.
或者我们选一个喜欢的场地
Or, we pick a place we like,
然后不要管爱因斯坦了
and don't worry about Einstein.
天啊  真人秀还真没错  新娘都疯了
Boy, reality TV is right; brides are crazy.
怎么样了啊  在家跟俩孩子待着
So, how has it been, being home with two kids?
累死人  但成就感满满
Oh, tiring, but super rewarding.
就像普拉提课程  我懂
Oh, like Pilates, yeah, got it.
说实话  我们都回工作岗位后会挺难吧
Honestly, it's gonna be hard when we both go back to work.
我在考虑或许我们俩人中
I've been thinking maybe it would be better
有一个人专职留在家带孩子
if one of us decided to stay home.
是吗  我就是佣人带大的  你看我
I don't know, I was raised by servants, and look at me.
我真的说不上你是觉得好还是不好
I literally can't tell if you think that's good or bad.
一方面来说  他们在我浴缸里加满了香精油
Well, on one hand, they filled my tub with scented oils
还会给我加蜂蜜的点心  而另一方面
and brought me honeyed sweets; on the other hand,
我二十多岁了却无法与女人直接对谈
I spent my twenties incapable of talking to women.
所以你懂吧  好坏参半
So you know, pros and cons.
我纠结的是
Here's my dilemma:
我有点想在家当家庭煮夫
I... kind of want to stay home.
但伯纳黛特比我更会带孩子
But Bernadette is a way better parent than I am.
等等  那伯纳黛特有想当主妇吗
Wait, does Bernadette want to stay home?
我不知道  她对事业投入了许多心血
I don't know. She's really invested in her career,
而且很有成绩
and she's doing great.
我觉得应该我在家
I think it should be me.
我敬佩你  霍华德
Wow, I admire you, Howard.
要我可能就很困难
I-It would be hard for me
让我这么突破传统性别角色藩篱
to buck traditional gender roles like that.
你这个月看了两次泰勒·斯威夫特的演唱会吧
Didn't you see Taylor Swift twice this month?
她的歌词以女孩恋爱/分手后的心情为主
是因为她人美  不是因为歌词仿佛在唱我
Yeah, because she's hot, not because she sings my truth.
爱因斯坦坐过这其中的任何一张椅子吗
Did Albert Einstein ever sit in any of these chairs?
这些椅子应该都没那么老
I think these are fairly new.
但霍金教授常来这里吃
But Stephen Hawking's eaten here a lot.
但他都是自带[轮]椅来的啊
Yeah, but he brings his own chair, you know?
这里感觉好完美啊
Well, it seems kind of perfect,
而且离你办公室又近
and it's close enough to your office,
你可以使用你喜欢的洗手间
so you can use the bathroom you like.
我把自动冲水的感应器用贴纸贴上
Mm. I put a sticker over the auto-flush,
这样就不会被突然吓到
so it doesn't startle me.
这是我的名片  两位先好好谈谈
Here's my card. Why don't you two talk it over,
我趁这时间去问问看我们的汤匙
and I will check to see if our soup spoons
是否"深度多过宽度"
are "Deeper than they are wide."
干嘛  深的是勺子  不是汤匙
What? Too deep is a ladle, not a spoon.
我好喜欢这里
I really like it.
我也得承认  我也很喜欢
Mm. Oh, I must admit, I do, as well.
你看这些人的画像看起来都多阴郁
I-- look at how somber all the men in these portraits are.
感觉为我们的婚礼定下了良好的基调
I feel like that sets a good tone for our wedding.
那是莱纳德吗
Is that Leonard?
不  才不是  这些都是已逝的杰出科学家
Oh, no, no, these are all dead, accomplished scientists.
莱纳德最多只能做到其中一项
Leonard will only ever be one of those things.
我是说莱纳德与佩妮就在那里
I mean, Leonard and Penny are right there.
但他上周跟我说他看了我们的会员申请
But he told me he checked on our membership just last week,
我们还在顺位400多名呢
and we were still 400th in line.
我相信他会有个无罪的合理解释
I'm sure there's an innocent explanation
听完绝对不会毁了我一天心情
that won't ruin my day at all.
莱纳德
Leonard.
-是你们啊  -你们来啦
- Oh, hey. ?- Hey.
你们怎么进来这里吃饭的
How did you get in here?
这话什么意思  莱纳德是会员啊
What do you mean? Leonard's a member.
你跟我说这里特别难申请啊
You told me it was incredibly exclusive.
听我说  是这样的...  我撒谎了
Y-Yeah, look, about that, I lied.
等等  你也跟我说这里很难申请啊
Hey, wait, you told me it was exclusive, too.
我用一个谎来躲开了他还迷到了你
I avoided him and impressed you, all with the same lie.
服了  霍夫斯塔德  看不出你这么厉害
Damn, Hofstadter, didn't think you had it in you.
现在我不知道该对这里作何感想了
Well, I'm not sure I know how I feel about this place now.
那千万别回头
Then don't turn around.
库珀
Cooper!
太好了  你在这
Oh, good, you're here.
有一件事
There's... something
我想跟你谈谈
I want to talk to you about.
我们绝对不会在厕所里放电视
We're not putting a TV in the bathroom.
人们就是这么得痔疮的
That's how you get hemorrhoids.
不是啦  是重要的事
No, this is important.
我在想或许我们俩其中一个
Uh, I was thinking maybe one of us should
应该留在家里全职带小孩
stay home full-time, with the kids.
这下可好  我得放弃我的工作
Oh great, so I have to give up my job
与我一直以来努力的成果吗
and everything I've worked for?
其实我想的是我留在家
Actually, I was thinking I should stay home.
所以我得抛下我孩子  回到工作岗位
Oh, so I have to abandon my children and go back to work,
然后你在家跟孩子们建立感情吗
while you get to stay home and bond with them?
可是你才说你不想留在家啊
You just said you didn't want to.
不  我不想要被迫要  但如果我想要  我就能要
No, I don't want to have to, but if I want to, I should get to.
那你想要吗
Do you want to?
或许有呢
Maybe I do.
那如果我也想要呢
What if I also want to?
我不知道啊  我们不能都留在家吧
Well, I don't know, we can't both stay home.
你不觉得该由你回去工作吗
Don't you think you should go back to work,
因为你赚的钱比我多啊
because you make more money?
那你不觉得你应该多挣点钱吗
Don't you think you should make more money?
我觉得你这样很性别歧视啊
I think it's pretty sexist of you to say
觉得当爸爸的就不能在家带小孩
a dad can't stay home with his children.
你知道还有什么很性别歧视吗  忍着[吸"鸟"]
You know what else is sexist, the phrase "Suck it,"
但就是这样
yet, here we are.
真没想到莱纳德会骗我
I can't believe Leonard lied to me.
接下来还会发现他说过什么谎
What are we gonna find out next,
他其实没有乳糖不耐症吗
that he's not really lactose intolerant, hmm?
他不是放屁  只是跟隐形的小号手是好朋友
He's just friends with an invisible trumpet player?
我知道你不高兴  但如果我们想订那俱乐部
I know you're upset, but if we want to book the Athenaeum,
我们现在就得订  然后我跟你保证
we really should do it now, and then, I promise,
我们会有余生让你慢慢抱怨莱纳德
we'll have our whole lives to complain about Leonard.
某人先开始说结婚誓词啦
Aw, somebody got a head start on her vows.
那我们达成共识了吗
So do we agree?
我们要在那里举行仪式吗
Do we want to get married there?
我不知道了
I don't know.
爱因斯坦曾是会员
I mean, Einstein was a member.
我喜欢这点
I like that.
你懂吧  可是...
You know? But...
但莱纳德也是会员  真的让我"炒鸡不爽"
Leonard's a member, and that really steams my clams.
我就喜欢你用地方方言的时候
Oh, I love it when you're folksy.
我就直接打电话订了
I'm just gonna call.
而另一方面呢  在莱纳德背叛我们的地方
On the other hand, shaming Leonard during our wedding
结婚并羞辱他
at the very place he betrayed me
感觉也十分的美妙
does have a beautiful symmetry to it.
不错  那会是你以人夫身份做的首件小肚鸡肠事
That's nice, it'll be your first petty act as a married man.
你好  是凯瑟琳吗
Uh-- oh, hi, Kathleen?
我是早先去你那里的艾米
Yeah, this is Amy from earlier.
我想先跟你预定5月12号那天的场地
I'd like to go ahead and reserve May 12.
不过那也是我们的大喜之日
Although, it is our wedding.
或许不该把重心都放在复仇上
I-- maybe it shouldn't be all about revenge.
好的
Oh, I see.
行  谢谢你
Okay, t-thanks.
有人订走了我们的日子
Someone booked our date.
什么
Uh... What?
谁
Who?
哎哟哟
Well, well, well.
这下可真难办了
This is a pickle.
是啊  所以...
Yes, so,
如果你能把你的生日派对移地举办
if you will just move your birthday party
那这就最好不过了
to a different location, everything will be fine.
这挺麻烦啊
Ugh, I-it's tricky.
我不想将我的派对改址
I don't want to move my party,
但我也不想帮你忙
but I also don't want to help you--
等等  我没有麻烦啊
oh, wait, I don't have a problem.
不  是我有
No. I do.
是啊  你麻烦大了
Yeah, you do.
早上好
Morning.
你们都去哪儿逛了
Hey, where you been?
没去什么特别的地方
Oh, nowhere special.
就是公园  农贸市场
Just the park, the farmer's market,
然后我们上了轻轨金线到唐人街去了
then we hopped on the Gold Line to Chinatown
因为让孩子们感受其他文化
because it's important for the kids
是很重要的
to experience other cultures.
你又做了些什么
What have you been doing?
现在才早上8点  睡觉
It's 8:00 A.M. Sleeping.
孩子们也是
Oh. So are the kids.
这一点应该是随你
I guess they take after you.
你只是想证明你会做得比我好
You're just trying to prove that you'd do a better job than me.
你刚睡醒就这么机灵啊
You're pretty sharp having just woken up.
霍华德  你我都清楚  你无法保持这个状态
Howard, we both know you can't keep up this pace.
到今天下午你就会昏睡在沙发上
By this afternoon you're gonna be passed out on the couch
到时我就得照顾三个累坏了的宝宝
and I'm gonna have three exhausted babies to deal with.
才不会  我能应付
Not true. I got this.
事实上  不如你今天请假休息吧
You know, in fact, why don't you take the day off?
好吧  或许我可以跟佩妮吃午餐
Mm, fine. Maybe I'll have lunch with Penny.
慢慢来
Take your time.
去做个按摩
Get a massage.
这是你应得的  毕竟你睡了那么多
You deserve it after all the sleep you've been getting.
也许巴里会改变主意
Maybe Barry will change his mind.
我深表怀疑
Hmm? Oh, I doubt it.
我对他的工作成果说了一些很不公道的话
I said some pretty unprofessional things about his work.
可能连"S"[屎]开头的词都用上了
I may have even used the "S" word.
"水"准以下吗
Subpar?
我不自豪  但我也是有脾气的
I'm not proud of it, Amy, but I have a temper.
其实我们也可以选别的日子
Well, I suppose we could pick a different date.
你可是花了九个月才选中那一天
Well, it took you nine months to choose that one.
我不如重选个老公算了
I'll pick a different husband first.
我想为雅典娜学术俱乐部的事道歉
Hey, I-I just, I wanted to apologize about the Athenaeum.
你之前为什么骗我
Why did you lie to me?
我也不知道
I don't know.
一开始是好玩
It just seemed funny at first
随着时间过去  变得更好玩了
and then the longer it went on, funnier it got.
所以  大概就是这个原因
So, yeah, I guess that's why.
这可算不上道歉吧
That's not much of an apology.
对  因为他不是真的心怀歉意
Yeah, because he's not really sorry.
显然  他想去一个没有我的地方
Obviously, he wanted a place to go where I wouldn't be
全世界的室外这么大  他还觉得不够
and apparently all of outside wasn't enough for him.
别这样  我真的不好受
Come on. I-I do feel bad.
为什么  你最好的朋友伤你心了吗
Why? Did your best friend hurt your feelings?
拜托  谢尔顿
Come on-- Sheldon.
听着  我现在只有空对付一个混蛋
Look, I only have time to deal with one jerk right now
-那就是巴里·克里普奇  -什么
- and that's Barry Kripke. - What?
他在我们婚礼日那天预订了雅典娜学术俱乐部
He has the Athenaeum booked for our wedding date
不愿意让给我们
and he won't give it up.
没错  所以请你离开  否则我就要生气了
Yeah, so if you could just please leave before I get angry
会说出令自己后悔的话来评价你的长相  身高
and say something I will regret about your face, your height,
个人卫生  或是你的科学成果
your personal hygiene or the fact that your science,
虽然有一定用途  但缺乏派头
while serviceable, lacks panache.
这其实是你对我成果说过的
That's actually one of the nicest things
最动听的评价了
you've ever said about my work.
现在我后悔了  再见
And now I regret it. Good-bye.
你在这儿呢
Hey. There you are.
我就想在我们出去吃午餐前
Yeah, I just wanted to stop in and see my office
来我办公室看一眼
before we went to lunch.
再过几周  你就回来全职上班了  对吧
Just a few more weeks, you'll be back full-time, huh?
是啊
Yeah.
你这可不是开心的语气
Uh-oh. That wasn't a happy "yeah."
是我邀莱纳德去健身房时  勉强答应的语气
That was a "Hey, Leonard, do you want to go to the gym?" yeah.
我一直在想  也许我更想待在家
I've just been thinking that maybe I'd rather
照顾孩子  当个好妈妈
stay home with the kids and be a mom.
这可是重大决定
Wow. That's big.
我知道
I know.
罗斯滕科斯基博士
Dr. Rostenkowski.
抱歉  我不知道你回来了
I'm sorry, I didn't know you were back.
不是的
Oh, I'm not.
我只是来找佩妮吃午餐
I just came to meet Penny for lunch.
需要我为你端咖啡或水来吗
Is there anything I can get you? Coffee? Water?
-不用了  我们准备...  -咖啡听起来不错
- No, I think we're just gonna... - Coffee sounds good.
-冷萃  加杏仁奶  -完美
- Cold brew, almond milk? - Perfect.
不用帮我准备了
Nothing-nothing for me.
好奇怪
It's weird.
我离开这么久  却一点都不怀念这里
I've been away so long I don't miss any of this.
抱歉打扰你了
Sorry to bother you.
李博士听说你来了  想问你个事
Dr. Lee heard you were here and had a quick question.
好吧  接通他
Fine. Put him on.
杰罗德  最近怎么样
Jerold, what's going on?
希望你没有毁了我的研究
Hope you're not screwing up my research.
你正在骑单车吗
You calling from a bike ride?
因为你正在迅速倒骑[气势减弱]
'Cause you're backpedaling hard.
好吧  发邮件给我  我这就看看
All right, fine. E-mail it over. I'll take a look.
不好意思  刚说到哪儿了
Oh, sorry. Where were we?
很爱你的孩子们  不想念工作
Love your kids. Don't miss your job.
对  对
Right, right.
世间万物都无法与之相比
There's nothing in the world
抱着自己熟睡的宝宝
like holding your sleeping baby,
知道你让他感到安全
knowing you make him feel safe and then--
太好了  你拿我爱吃的曲奇饼来了
Oh, good, you got the little cookies I like.
我也想吃曲奇饼
I wouldn't mind a cookie.
他已经走了  好吧
And he's gone. Okay.
克里普奇
Hey, Kripke.
你好  霍夫斯塔德
Hello, Hofstadter.
你怎么亲自在清洗这个
Why are you cleaning that out yourself?
没有研究生帮你吗
Don't you have grad students?
拜托  总不能所有脏活都让研究生干
Come on, I can't make my grad students do every dirty job
应该说人力资源部门主管明文禁止我这么做
or so I've been told in writing by the head of Human Resources.
好吧  听我说
Fair enough. Uh, so, look,
我是来请求你把雅典娜学术俱乐部
I'm here to ask you to give Sheldon and Amy
让给谢尔顿和艾米举行婚礼
the Athenaeum for their wedding.
我为什么要这么做
Why would I do that?
因为内心深处  你是一个很好的人
Because deep down, Barry, you're a really good guy.
但我真是好人吗
But am I?
好吧  有什么条件
Fine. What's it gonna take?
巴里  我来再问你一次...
Barry, I've come to ask one more...
莱纳德
Leonard?
你怎么在干这个
Wh-Why are you doing that?
因为巴里在内心深处并不是个好人
Because deep down Barry is not a good guy.
他叫你清洗装辐照油脂的桶吗
He's making you clean out barrels of irradiated grease?
是的
Yeah.
我跟他做了笔交易
I made a deal with him
让他把雅典娜学术俱乐部让给你举办婚礼
to get you the Athenaeum for your wedding.
你为什么要这么做
Why would you do that?
因为我之前骗了你  很混蛋
Because I was a jerk for lying to you before
再说  你是我最好的朋友
and besides, you're my best friend.
我希望你能拥有梦想中的婚礼
I want you to have the wedding of your dreams.
在火星上吗
On Mars?
好吧  我希望艾米能拥有梦想中的婚礼
Okay, I want Amy to have the wedding of her dreams.
谢谢你
Well, thank you.
但我不想让你干这个
But I don't want you to do this.
没关系
No, it's okay.
有关系
No, it's not.
我们不能让巴里赢
We're not going to let Barry win.
那我们要怎么做
Well, what are we going to do?
我们俩的智商加起来有360
We have a combined IQ of 360.
要是那辐射让你大脑变异成超级大脑  还会更高
Perhaps more if that radiation gave you a super brain.
知道吗  你说得对
You know what? You're right.
我们同心协力就一定能碾压巴里·克里普奇
If we work together we could totally outsmart Barry Kripke.
莱纳德  我鼻子痒  怎么办
Leonard, my nose itches. What do I do?
天啊
Oh, boy.
我昏睡得不省人事
I really passed out hard.
可不是嘛
Yeah, tell me about it.
就算孩子们尖叫有人杀人
The kids could've screamed bloody murder
你也不会醒
and you wouldn't have woken up.
这我知道  因为他们真的尖叫了
Which I know because they did.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我怎么会以为自己能搞定
Why did I think I could do this on my own?
别太责怪自己了
Hey, don't beat yourself up.
照顾小孩是很辛苦的
Parenting is hard.
我今天看到和闻到的东西
Like, I've seen and smelled things today
已经深深烙印在我的脑海里了
that I cannot unsee or unsmell.
谢谢你来帮我
Thanks for covering for me.
真的  他明明只喝奶
No, I mean he only drinks milk.
那些颜色是怎么来的
Like, where are the colors coming from?
现在几点了
What time is it?
快6点了
Uh, it's almost 6:00.
好  伯纳黛特快回家了
Okay. Bernadette's gonna be home soon.
我们得分工合作
We got to divide and conquer.
我去做晚餐  你照看孩子们
I'll make dinner. You watch the kids.
孩子们睡着了
Uh, kids are asleep.
太好了  那你去做晚餐
Great, then you make dinner.
好消息  艾米
Hey, good news, Amy.
我们拿到俱乐部的场地了
We got the Athenaeum.
天啊
Oh, my gosh.
太棒了
That's amazing.
你怎么让巴里改变主意的
How'd you get Barry to change his mind?
没有莱纳德  我一个人无法做到
Well, I couldn't have done it without Leonard.
你真应该看看我们在里面的英姿
Boy, you should've seen us in there.
我们就像蝙蝠侠和罗宾一样
We were like Batman and Robin.
为什么我得当罗宾
Why do I have to be Robin?
如果你还要弱弱地问  那你就是罗宾
If you have to ask, you're Robin.
发生什么了
What happened?
我们刷洗完几个装过辐照油脂的桶
Well, we scrubbed out some barrels of irradiated grease,
再用安全淋浴洗净身上后
rinsed off in a safety shower
就去给了巴里·克里普奇一点颜色瞧瞧
and then told Barry Kripke what is what.
他就这样让步了吗
And he just gave in?
我们还同意邀请他来参加婚礼
Well, we agreed to invite him to the wedding.
好吧  没问题
Okay. No problem.
-他还能带一个伴儿出席  -行啊
- And he gets to bring a date. ?- Yeah.
合情合理
Well, that's reasonable.
如果"女伴"按小时收费  我们得出钱
A-And if she charges by the hour, we have to cover it.
你们还答应了什么
What else did you agree to?
你知道巴里有宛如天籁的嗓音吗
Well, um, you know how Barry has the voice of an angel?
他绝不能在我们婚礼上献唱
He is not singing at our wedding.
他只想唱经典老歌《飞》
He only wants to sing "Volare."
原来是《飞》啊
Oh, "Volare"
我还以为是《灰》什么的
That's what he was saying.
我还真没听懂他的发音
Boy, I didn't, I did not get that.
我很感激你们所做的一切
Guys, I appreciate everything you did,
但我们能找到另一个同样赞的场地
but we can find another location that's just as good.
比如日式花园或天文馆
Maybe the Japanese garden or the planetarium.
天文馆
The planetarium.
我之前都没想到呢
I hadn't thought about that.
这选择更棒了
That's even better.
等等  什么
Wait, what?
我还为你刷洗了污泥
I scrubbed sludge for you.
现在没准我都带有点放射性了
I may be slightly radioactive.
你太夸张啦
Oh, you're exaggerating.
别让他碰镀银餐具[会残留]
Don't let him touch the silverware.
拉杰为什么睡倒在我们家沙发上
Why is Raj asleep on our couch?
我需要帮忙  于是他就过来了
Oh. I needed some help so he came by,
陪孩子们玩了会  给他们读故事
played with the kids, read them some stories,
哄他们睡午觉  还做了晚饭
put them down for their nap and made dinner.
你做了什么
What'd you do?
吃晚饭
Ate dinner.
听着  我想我不是
Okay, look, I don't think I'm cut out
当全职爸爸的料
to be a stay-at-home dad.
既然你想  那应该让你留在家里
And since you want to, you should stay home.
我确实想待在家
I-I do definitely want to,
但我知道这对你很重要  而且只是过了一天
but I know how much this means to you and it was just one day.
所以  别放弃哦
So, don't give up.
你也不想待在家里
You don't want to stay home, either.
是不是
Do you?
我今天路过办公室  他们给我
When I went by the office they gave me
端咖啡和曲奇来  也没人尿在我身上
coffee and cookies and no one peed on me.
我好想念那一切
I miss that so much.
我很爱孩子们  但我也很热爱我的工作
Well, I love the kids, but I also love my job.
以及睡觉
And sleep.
我知道  我在办公室的沙发小睡了两小时
I know. I took a two-hour nap on the couch in my office.
我在客厅地板上小睡了三小时
I took a three-hour nap on the floor in the living room.
你现在感觉如何
How do you feel now?
说实话吗  还是很累
Honestly? Still tired.
我也是
Me, too.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
我们会想出解决办法的
And we'll figure this all out.
是啊
Yeah.
大家都睡着了
Everyone's asleep.
你想到楼上去...
You want to head upstairs and...
你懂的
...you know.
我们就在这里进行吧
Let's just do it right here.
我喜欢你的小脑袋瓜
Oh, oh, I like the way you think.